Christophe Foyer

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 • France: (+33) 6 78 56 99 03 French and US citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

Summary:

Mechanical Engineering graduate with experience in projects in mechatronics, software, and aerospace engineering. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

CAD, FEA and CFD

Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)

Electrical System Design

Linux Server Management and Software Development

Education:

Washington University in Saint Louis

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering; Minor in Energy Engineering

Dean's List (Fall 2014, Fall 2017)

Saint Louis, United States Aug 2014 – Dec 2017 3.14/4.00 GPA

RWTH Aachen 'Renewable Energy Technology' | 'Mechatronics and Product Innovation'

School for International Training

Study abroad in Renewable Energy Engineering and Resource Economics

Caen. France Sep 2010 – Jul 2013

Aachen, Germany Jun 2017 - Jul 2017

Reykjavik, Iceland Jun 2015 – Aug 2015

Lycée Sainte Marie Série S (Science specialization)

French Baccalauréat: "Mention Bien" (with honors)

Relevant Experience:

Tata Steel Europe

Mechanical Engineering Intern

Ijmuiden, Netherlands Apr 2018 – July 2018

- Built and implemented a real-time temperature simulation of a great number of steel slabs.
- Creation of a modular software framework and implementation of a heat transport model coded in Python.
- Performance optimization for real-time processing and visualization for large datasets.

Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Mar 2016 – Dec 2017 Aug 2016 – May 2017

Co-Founder and Systems Team Lead **Treasurer**

Event Planner

Co-led the team to 12th place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition, and 1st in the US Midwest

- Designed aircraft internal system including battery and motor selection with the systems team
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to buy supplies and organize travel to the competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and set project deadlines

American Society of Mechanical Engineers

Washington University in St. Louis, USA Sep 2016 – May 2017

- Assisted ASME members with ongoing projects by advising them on manufacturing and component selection
- Researched potential STEM-related speakers to fit within budget constraint, presented reasons to fund Michio Kaku's visit to campus, and secured a date for his visit

Skills and Abilities:

CAD / FEA / CFD: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk Nettfab, XFLR5

Programming Languages: Matlab, Simulink, Python, Arduino C (C/C++), HTML

Fabrication: 3D-Printing (FDM), Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite Manufacturing

Software: Microsoft Office Suite, SVN, Windows, Linux

Languages: Bilingual French / English; Basic German and Icelandic

Academic Projects:

Senior Design Project – Low-Cost CPV

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

- Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB
- Development of a sunlight tracking circuit and coding using Arduino
- Creation of a working proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%.

Independent Projects:

Printable Folding Tricopter

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Design of a folding tricopter frame for FDM printing:

- Design of interlocking printable parts using Solidworks and Autodesk Nettfab to be 3D-printed
- Designed to minimize weight and exterior volume while maximizing payload space.

Motor Test Stand Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a motor test stand for Wash. U Design/Build/Fly:

- GUI development, serial communication protocol and sensor integration
- Coded in Python and Arduino C, packaged in .exe format for easy deployment to new Windows installations
- Measures motor-propeller-battery system RPM, current, voltage, and thrust and logs output to CSV

Oct 2016 - Dec 2017 **Electric Longboard**

Design and construction of a custom built electric longboard for daily usage and international travel:

- CAD, FEA, and part fabrication in aluminum and FDM printing of plastic parts
- Electrical powertrain design including component selection balancing efficiency and cost
- Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations.

Naïve Bayes Classifier

Jun 2016 – Aug 2016

Coding of a Naïve Bayes Classifier for financial forecasting using machine learning:

- Average accuracy of 67% on pima-indians-diabetes test dataset.
- Achieved an accuracy of 51.51% when tasked to forecast wheat price trends (low accuracy due to limitations with regards to dataset size; which is a different, ongoing project)

IRIS Voice Recognition and Home Automation

Jan 2015 – May 2017

Custom-built smart home and media center system:

- Voice recognition using google API interfacing with connected microphones
- Coded in Python 2.7 on a Raspberry Pi running a Linux-based OS (added support for Windows and OSX)
- Control over house appliances (both wired an wirelessly) and interfacing with Open Source Media Center

Robotics Test Platform Dec 2013 – Jan 2015

Design, coding, and construction of an internet-controlled robot used for autonomous sensing and navigation testing:

- Coded in Python on Linux-based microcontrollers
- Frontend: webpage coding in HTML and UI design
- Backend: hardware interfacing and communication over WebSocket between the webserver and the local microcontroller.
- Experiments in visual odometry using OpenCV and ROS (ongoing)

Volunteering and Work Experience:

Domaine du Vivier

Ishinomaki, Japan **ICC** May 2014 Volunteer

Construction of wooden terraces for the local community in a region devastated by the 2011 tsunami.

Seasonal farm hand

Le Mesnil Mauger, France Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

- Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work
- Driver for the tossing of the hay and the loading of hay bales during the summer